<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lord Deputy and Councell</title>
            <title>Proclamations</title>
            <author>Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1634</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04106</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14208A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S101141</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99836964</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99836964</idno>
            <idno type="VID">1265</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04106)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 1265)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1384:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lord Deputy and Councell</title>
                  <title>Proclamations</title>
                  <author>Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By the Society of Stationers, printed by the Kings most excellent Majestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1634.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Concerning heralds' fees at funerals."--STC.</note>
                  <note>Another edition of STC 14208, published in 1627.</note>
                  <note>Torn, with some loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Heraldry --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  Proclamations --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-10</date>
            <label>Aptara</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="decree">
            <pb facs="tcp:1265:1"/>
            <head>By the Lord Depu<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and Councell.</head>
            <opener>HENRY FALKLAND.</opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſtie, hath by his <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ers directed vnto Vs the <hi>Lord Deputie,</hi> ſignified his Princely pleaſure, that
calling to Our aſsiſtance, ſuch of the <hi>Nobility</hi> &amp; <hi>Councells</hi> We ſhould thinke fit, a ſpeedy redreſſe &amp; reformation ſhould be made of
divers abuſes &amp; diſorders concerning <hi>Armes</hi> &amp; <hi>Armory</hi> in this his Majeſties <hi>Realme</hi> of <hi>Ireland,</hi> occaſioned partly through the boldnes
of ſome Mechanicall perſons, who preſume to medle in <hi>Irmory</hi> without directio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> from the <hi>King</hi> of <hi>Armes</hi> of the ſame, being the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per
<hi>Officer</hi> appointed to attend that ſervice, And partly t<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>rough the <hi>Nobility</hi> &amp; <hi>Gentrie</hi> themſelves, who have of late (of which his
Majeſt. taketh notice) wholly in a maner laid aſide all Fu<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>all rites &amp; ceremonies, by means wherof (as his Majeſt. in his Princely &amp;
deep judgment moſt wiſely fore-ſeeth) the Houſes of the <hi>Nobility</hi> &amp; <hi>Gentrie</hi> cannot but in a ſhort time grow into many perplexi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties
&amp; confuſed diſorders in their <hi>Armes</hi> &amp; <hi>Petegrees,</hi> for want of the vſe of <hi>Armes</hi> at Obſequies &amp; Funerals, and for want of the entrie of the day of the
Deceaſe, Matches, &amp; Iſſues of the deceaſed parties. And whereas his moſt Excellent Maieſtie hath likewiſe bin pleaſed to command that for direction in
the premiſes, vſe ſhoul<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> be made of an Order or Decree ſet forth in <hi>Print</hi> by the <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ight <hi>Hon.</hi> the <hi>Lords Commiſs.</hi> of the <hi>Earle Marſhals</hi> Office of <hi>England</hi> for
the reforming of the like abuſes there, <hi>Dated</hi> the 10. day of <hi>Nov.</hi> in the 16. ye<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> of the Raigne of <hi>King</hi> IAMES of bleſſed memory, authorizing vs thereby
to lay downe ſome ſuch courſe and order for the redreſſe of the former e<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ormities, &amp; for the ſupport of the <hi>Officers</hi> of <hi>Armes</hi> here as ſhall be thought
fit and reaſonable to ſtand with the ſtate &amp; condition of this <hi>Kingdome,</hi> with proviſion, that the ſaid <hi>King</hi> of <hi>Armes</hi> have ſatisfaction for ſuch Funeralls
of the <hi>Lords, Knights,</hi> and other of eminent place &amp; quality, as of late have not made vſe of his Office, as by his <hi>Maieſties</hi> ſaid <hi>Letters</hi> dated at <hi>VVeſtminſter</hi>
the 7. day of <hi>Aprill,</hi> in the third yeare of his raigne, &amp; enrol'd in the <hi>Roles</hi> of <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>s <hi>Maieſties</hi> high Court of <hi>Chancery</hi> here, more at large appeareth We there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
in obedience to his <hi>Maiesties</hi> ſaid commandement, having taken a due &amp; co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſiderat view of the fore-named Printed Order, &amp; maturely pondered the
other circumſtances enioyned by his <hi>Maieſtie,</hi> doe order, decree &amp; ordaine, th<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> aſwell for the good of the ſaid <hi>Nobilitie</hi> &amp; <hi>Gentrie</hi> of this <hi>Kingdome,</hi> as for
the honour of the <hi>Kingdome</hi> it ſelfe, leſt the moſt ancient &amp; laudable vſe of <hi>Armes</hi> ſhould wholly be laid aſide, &amp; ſo no outward token or Embleme be
left to make a difference between <hi>Familie,</hi> &amp; <hi>Familie,</hi> or to diſtinguiſh betw<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>n the moſt honorable <hi>Nobleman</hi> &amp; the pooreſt <hi>Artificer:</hi> That all <hi>Noblemen</hi>
&amp; <hi>Noble-women, Baronets, Knights, Eſquires,</hi> &amp; <hi>Gentlemen</hi>
               <note n="1" place="margin">Being in nu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber twentie foure.</note> co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>tained in a ſchedule hereunto annexed: And all other that fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> henceforth ſhalbe either ſilent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly
buried in the night-time by torch-light, or otherwiſe by day or night time without either Scuchions or other atchievements, or without attendance of
an <hi>Officer</hi> of <hi>Armes,</hi> ſhall nevertheleſſe immediatly after the death and burial of every ſuch Defunct, returne a true Certificate of the <hi>Matches, Iſsues,</hi> and
times of deceaſe, with their <hi>Armes</hi> which of right in their life they bore; for the which they ſhall pay vnto the ſaid King of <hi>Armes</hi> (though by a Clauſe of
his <hi>Letters-Patents</hi> he clayme the ſame Fees that are payde in<note n="2" place="margin">Being dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble the Fees here reſerued in euery ſtate and degree.</note> 
               <hi>England</hi>) ſuch Fees as we have &amp; doe hereby ſet down and appoint, <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>iz.</hi> Euery GENTLE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>MAN
<hi>twenty ſhillings Engliſh.</hi> Euery ESQVIER <hi>three pounds ſixe ſhillings &amp; <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ight pence Engliſh.</hi> Euery KNIGHT <hi>five pounds Engl.</hi> Euery BARONET &amp; BAN<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>NERET
<hi>ſix pounds thirteene ſhillings &amp; foure pence Engliſh.</hi> Euery BARON or BARONESSE <hi>twelve pounds ten ſhillings Engliſh.</hi> Euery BISHOP <hi>twelve pounds ten
ſhillings Engliſh.</hi> Euery VICOVNT or VICOVNTESSE <hi>fifteene pounds Engliſh</hi> Euery <hi>EARLE</hi> or <hi>COVNTESSE</hi> ſeauenteene pounds tenne ſhillings <hi>Engliſh.</hi> Euery
MARQVES or MARCHIONESSE <hi>twenty pounds Engliſh.</hi> Euery DVKE or DVTCHES <hi>twenty two pounds ten ſhill. Engl.</hi> And euery ARCHBISHOP <hi>twenty two
pounds ten ſhillings Engliſh.</hi> All which ſaid ſeuerall ſummes of money are to be payd to the ſaid King of <hi>Armes,</hi> or his Aſsignes, being orderly demaunded,
after the buriall of euery ſuch Defunct by the <hi>Heires, Executors,</hi> or <hi>Adminiſtrators</hi> of all &amp; euery Perſons of the degrees aforeſaid. The which Certificates
&amp; Fees, if they ſhall refuſe to returne &amp; pay (the Fees being reduced ſo low vnder that which is payd in <hi>England,</hi> &amp; ſo by vs according to his <hi>Majeſties Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veat,</hi>
thought fit &amp; reaſonable to ſtand with the ſtate of the <hi>Kingdom</hi>). W<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> vpon complaint made by the King of <hi>Armes,</hi> or his Aſsignes to Vs, take
ſuch further order therein, as ſhalbe meet &amp; expedient for the accompliſhment of his <hi>Majeſties</hi> commandement. And <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> doe ſtraightly charge
the ſaid King of <hi>Armes,</hi> who now is, or hereafter ſhall be, to make true &amp; faire entries of the Certificates above-named ſo returned into his Office (they
paying ſuch Fees as are before ſet down by theſe preſents.<note n="3" place="margin">Perſons of everall degrees whoſe Certifi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cates muſt bee entred without Fees.</note> And likewiſe to enter the like Certificates of all <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> whoſe eſtates in Land and goods
exceede not five hundred Markes <hi>Engliſh.</hi> And of all <hi>Ladies</hi> &amp; <hi>Gentlewomen</hi> vnder the degree of a <hi>Lady Baroneſſe</hi> as exactly as the reſt, paying no Fees at all.
(Provided that it be firſt duely proved before two of his <hi>Majeſties Iuſtices</hi> of the Peace or more, that the party is no more worth.) Which Certificates ſo
entred, may in future time determine &amp; end many queſtio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s that hereafter may ariſe, as by many examples of late time have bin ſeen in <hi>England.</hi>
               <note n="4" place="margin">Proviſion for ſome Knights, and Eſquiers.</note> Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided
alvvayes that if the Heires, Executors, or Adminiſtrators of any <hi>Knight</hi> or <hi>Eſquire</hi> ſhall pretend povertie or diſabilitie, and ſhall make the ſame ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare
by Petition vnto the <hi>Lord Deputy,</hi> or other <hi>Governour</hi> or <hi>Governours</hi> f<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> the time being, order ſhall be taken vpon due proofe made, that the Heires,
Executors or Adminiſtrators ſhalbe eaſed of paying the ſaid Fees (if ſo i<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſhalbe thought fit) and the Certificate notvvithſtanding entred as above. Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertheleſſe
if any of the degrees aforeſaid their Wives and Children ſhall <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>quire to have their <hi>Funerals</hi> honourably ſolemnized vvith the attendance of
one or both the <hi>Officers</hi> of <hi>Armes,</hi> according to their degrees, &amp; vvith ſuch other ceremonies as have in former times bin vſed,<note n="5" place="margin">The Offi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cers of Armes in England by the decree a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue ſpecified, are left at liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie in this caſe to make their compoſition as in former time.</note> That then they ſhall
pay the above-named Fees reſpectively vvith the addition of<note n="6" place="margin">It was two ſhillings the mile out, and two ſhillings the mile home<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, to the K. of Armes, and twelve pence the mile out &amp; twelve pence homeward to the other Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer before, ac<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cording to the cuſtome of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland.</note> 
               <hi>Twelue pe<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ce Engliſh</hi> the mile outvvard, and <hi>Twelue pence Engliſh</hi> the mile homevvard,
<note n="7" place="margin">It was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore xx. Nobles for blackes, &amp; Liveries for 4. Servants to the king of <hi>Armes</hi> &amp; a quarter as much beſide to the other Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer according to the cuſtome of England, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſide Fees in mo<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ney for everie degree, above double the fees within named.</note> and forty ſhillings Engliſh for Blacks, vvith entertainment of the <hi>Of<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>cer</hi> of <hi>Officers</hi> of <hi>Armes</hi> and their ſervants in the Funerall houſe, and meate for
their Horſes, as hath bin accuſtomed, &amp; vvith the accuſtomed &amp; ancient <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>quiſite of <hi>Hearſes</hi> vvith all their furniture vvhen any ſhalbe vſed, and the above
named Fees to ſtand for ſatisfaction to both for all demands. And for remedie of the former abuſes vvhich are daylie committed by <hi>Painters, Maſons, Gla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiers,
Goldſmiths, Cutters, Carvers,</hi> and the like, Wee doe ſtraightly charge <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>d commaund them throught this <hi>Realme,</hi> that they preſume not to meddle
vvith any matters of <hi>Armorie</hi> or <hi>Armes,</hi> except thoſe <hi>Armes</hi> that are ſo co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>monly knovvn as there is no likelyhood of error. And that no <hi>Painters,</hi> or other
perſon ſet forth any Funerals, or make any Scuchions, or other Funerall <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>orke, vvithout ſpeciall leave and approbation of the King of <hi>Armes,</hi> or his ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient
Deputy or Deputyes, as they vvill anſvvere the contrary at their pe<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Provided that ſuch as the ſaid King of <hi>Armes</hi> ſhall appoint to make Scuchi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons
and other Funerall vvorke, ſhall not exceede the ordinary Price no<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ſed in and about <hi>London,</hi> as the ſame ſhall be certified vnder the hands of tvvo
or more of the Kings of <hi>Armes</hi> there vvithin a yeare after the Date of the preſents. Which Certificate is to be entred vpon <hi>Record</hi> in his <hi>Majeſties</hi> high
Court of <hi>Chauncery</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ere. Given at his <hi>Majeſties</hi> Caſtle of <hi>Dublin</hi> the 4. o<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>uguſt, in the third yeare of his <hi>Majeſties</hi> Raigne. <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1627.</p>
            <list>
               <item>Adam Loftus Canc.</item>
               <item>Ia. Armachanus.</item>
               <item>Lanc. Dublin.</item>
               <item>R. Corke.</item>
               <item>Hen. Valentia.</item>
               <item>Thom. Cromwell.</item>
               <item>Dom. Kilmallocke.</item>
               <item>Thom. Baltinglaſſe.</item>
               <item>R. Ranelagh</item>
               <item>R. Dillon.</item>
               <item>Will Caulfield.</item>
               <item>Henr. Docwra.</item>
               <item>Fr. Aungier.</item>
               <item>Will. Parſons.</item>
               <item>Rich. Bolton.</item>
               <item>Dud. Norton.</item>
               <item>Char. Coote.</item>
               <item>Adam Loftus.</item>
            </list>
            <div type="price_list">
               <head>The Kings of Armes of England haue within the time preſcribed in this Decree, certified the prices of Funerall worke, as followeth,
The prices <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eing all Engliſh.</head>
               <list>
                  <head>Prices for Funerall worke.</head>
                  <item>A Great Banner. xl. ſhillings.</item>
                  <item>A Standart. xl. ſhillings.</item>
                  <item>A Penoune. xxvj. s. viij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Banneroll. xxvj. s. viij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Coate of Armes. xxvj. s. viij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Sword. x. ſhil.</item>
                  <item>A Target. x. ſhil.</item>
                  <item>A Creſt carved. xiij. s. iiij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Wreath. iij. s. iiij.</item>
                  <item>Mantles furniſhed. xx. ſhi<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Buckram Scuchion. ij. ſhi</item>
                  <item>A Buckram Scuchion with Coronet. ij. s. vj. <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Paper Scuchion. xi<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Paper Scuchion with a Coronet. xiii<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>.</item>
                  <item>A Badge. x<gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Scuchion on Taffata. <gap reason="illegible: torn page" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </item>
               </list>
               <list>
                  <head>Furniture for a Hearſe.</head>
                  <item>PEncilles a dozen. x. ſhill.</item>
                  <item>A Water Table. vj. ſhil. viij. d.</item>
                  <item>A water Table with ſupporters &amp; Coronet. x. s.</item>
                  <item>A Creſt on Paſtebord. xij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Scrole. iij. ſhil. iiij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Compartment. v. ſhil.</item>
                  <item>A Coronet to compaſſe the Hearſe. xxx. ſhil.</item>
                  <item>A Scuchion for the ſeeling. xiij. s. iiij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Staffe for Banner or Standart, xij. d.</item>
                  <item>A Conductors Staffe. vj. d.</item>
               </list>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Will. Seager Garter. Rich. S. George Clarenceux.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at <hi>Dublin</hi> by the Society of Stationers, Printer to the Kings moſt excellent Majeſtie, Anno Dom. 1634.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
